ARJUN K PRASAD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Software Developer with two years of experience in complex enterprise to minor inhouse applications. Have a strong grasp of industry standards and efficiency in methodologies such as Agile. Comfortable working on independent as well as in collaborative projects. Also possess four years of experience in various other fields with transferable skills.

arjun1237.kp@gmail.com

□ +91-7349622070

arjun-portfolio.vercel.app

github.com/arjun1237

in linkedin.com/in/arjun1237

119, Garden Villas, Bangalore-72

SKILLS



SOFT SKILLS



GAME DEV.

CHESS (UNDER PROGRESS)

[LINK]

Tech Stacks: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

SUDOKU SOLVER

[LINK]

Tech Stacks: React

Tech Stacks: React
Algorithms: Recursion, Backtracking

DOT.COM

[LINK]

Tech Stacks: Java

MINI PROJECTS

TRIVIA QUIZ

STIMER

[LINK]

CARDOM [LINK]

EXPERIENCE

INSTRUCTIONAL ASSOCIATE | APP DEVELOPER

MASAI SCHOOL, B'LORE

OCT 2020-PRESENT

- · Developed a Quiz App, that is currently being used by outgoing batch students for interview preparations.
- · Working on the Mongo Queries in the backend and redux in the frontend, has been the main focus of my involvement in the project.
- · Assisted faculties with answering queries of students in daily stand ups. Delivered lectures whenever required.

SHERPA (PART TIME)

MASAI SCHOOL, B'LORE

AUG 2020-OCT 2020

- · Clarified and fine-tuned JavaScript concepts as I guided junior batch students with their curriculum.
- · Helped analyze Algorithmic problems while I worked on students ability to examine and resolve them.

SERVER SUPPORT ENGINEER

HP ENTERPRISE, B'LORE

FFB 2019-JUNE 2019

- Successfully deployed nodes for several of HPE clients on their HPE Simplivity federation.
- · Was responsible for entire deployment including IP network analysis to checking the federation health on deployment.

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

FFX LTD., LYMPNE, UK

OCT 2017-NOV 2018

- Contributed to development and design of several user-friendly, in-house applications, including e-commerce website.
- Successfully developed RESTful APIs for the Epos System and E-Commerce Website, utilizing .NET Core framework.
- Expedited e-commerce webpage loading by few seconds on modification of a legacy algorithm, utilizing LINQ.
- Authored several MSTest for application debugging purpose for complex integrated applications.

EDUCATION

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT COURSE

MASAI SCHOOL, BANGALORE

APR 2020-OCT 2020

• Full Stack Development course with focus on MERN Stack.

MSC COMPUTER SCIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF KENT, CANTERBURY, UK

2016-2018

- Graduated with First Honours (Distinction).
- Emphasis on Java, Web-Development, Intelligence Systems.

BSC ANIMATION

MANIPAL UNIVERSITY, B'LORE BRANCH

2008-2011

- Obtained 7.85/10 CGPA.
- Major emphasis on Design and Visual Effects skills.

PROJECTS

MASAI REFRESH [LINK]

TEAM PROJECT

JAN 2021-PRESENT

- Developed a Quiz App that lets you take a quiz based on your preferred stack topic, and analyse results.
- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Assisted the team with creating APIs using ExpressJS, along with actively developing the Redux in the Frontend.}\\$
- Tech Stacks: React, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Material UI.

CHITRAKALA [LINK]

TEAM PROJECT

AUG 2020

- A ticket booking app that lets you select the movie of your choice, book ticket for a choosen date and time, at your ease.
- Designed and Developed the app. Contrived Schema and Handled Data using Local Storage and Context API
- Tech Stacks: React, Styled-Components

FFX E-COMMERCE WEBSITE [LINK]

TEAM PROJECT

JAN 2018-NOV 2018

- An E-Commerce Website for customers looking to buy power tools accessories and general construction consumables.
- · Created REST APIs. Worked on product comparison to enhance user experience. Assisted in developing product pages.
- Tech Stacks: C#.NET, MS-SQL, MongoDB, JQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.